この国の 人気の観光スポットです まだ　誰も見たことのない その屋敷を　ひと目　見ようと デントラ地区にある 樹海に囲まれた ゾルディック家の 屋敷があります ここには　暗殺一家で有名な 標高３７２２ｍの死火山 ククルーマウンテン
I must crush his will. His will to fight, his will to stand, his will to resist...
お前は　もう自由だ。
He's fast...
だが…。
I had no time to dodge!
一つだけ誓え。
But I can still block his attacks!
絶対に仲間を裏切るな　いいな？
Oh? He used Gyo?
うん。 誓うよ　裏切らない。
The moment I grasped his arm, he focused his aura there to block my attack.
絶対に。
You think you've outwitted me now?!
尊敬する父　シルバと語らい
What's the matter?
母親の反対を押し切って 再び　家を出たキルア
That was just a body blow.
ゴン達３人は キルアに会うため
If you focus your aura where I grab you, you leave yourself open everywhere else.
カナリアの案内で 執事室へと向かっていた
It's futile... In fact, you're only making
it harder on yourself.
もう　しばらく。 はぁ。 どんだけ歩けば　着くんだか。
Bisky was right!
ウチの人ったら また家出を許しちゃったのよ！ お義父様も　お義父様よ！ 断りもなく 勝手に　キルを解放しちゃうし！
One more hit to send you to hell!
私には相談なしに 勝手なことばかり！
Impossible! That was the hardest hit so far!
分かる？　ゴトー。
He shouldn't have been able to counter.
はい。 はぁ…　うぅ…。
But since he did, that means he
kept the damage to a minimum.
キル… キルは　今が一番大事な時なのよ。 どうして 分かってくれないのかしら。
He guessed I didn't intend to set off a bomb?
あの子だけは　手放したくないの！
No, that wasn't a guess. Hey, Bisky...
あそこよ。
He shrouds his hand in aura that's
stronger than the explosion. Oh... I get it.
あの屋敷か。 けど　まだ結構　距離あるな。
It's a technique that requires
a large aura reserve.
ねぇ　カナリア。
This is a good opportunity.
俺達を勝手に連れて来たから 叱られるんじゃないの？
By now, you should be able to tell.
私が　あなた達を 連れて来ていることは
Excellent reaction! You've almost perfected Gyo.
とっくに知られているはずです。 だから　覚悟の上です。
One more time, then.
何かあったら　俺が責任　負うよ。
Huh? Could you tell the difference? Yeah, you used less aura the second time.
キルア様 お待ちしておりました。
If he's just faking and planning
to attack you somewhere else, he probably won't use Gyo.
ゴトー！　ゴンは今　どこにいる？ お前　知ってるんだろ？ ゴン様と　お連れの　お２人は カナリアの案内で こちらへ向かっておられます。
If you can tell if his hand is covered
with Gyo when he grabs you, it'll be simpler for you to know
which attack you should block.
ホントか？
So that's it.
すぐに　いらっしゃいますので お部屋で　お待ちください。
You knew from my Gyo. Cunning.
ゴトー。 はい。 ゴンが来たら　すぐに呼べよ。
The shallow strategy you're using will backfire. If you're caught by Little Flower when
you aren't using enough aura to defend, a hit to the face will blow off your eyes,
nose, and mouth with no hope of repair.
申し訳ありません　キルア様
A hit to the arms or legs will incinerate skin,
severely damaging any nerves or muscle.
おっ！　やっと着いたぜ。
It's not possible for you to use Gyo to guard
against every attack that uses Gyo.
いらっしゃいませ。
Fighting you has made me see something... You have talent and a promising future.
奥様から連絡があり あなた方を正式な客人として
Don't you think it's meaningless to throw
all that away just for your pride?
迎えるように 申しつけられました。
Just give up, stupid kid! If he makes like he's going to use
both hands to blow you up, that's a red light.
ここが屋敷じゃないのか。
Sorry, Bisky and Killua.
ええ　執事用の住まいよ。
I'm gonna be selfish here.
さぁ　ごゆっくりと おくつろぎください。
I have to give it a try...
心遣いは嬉しいが　俺達は キルアに会うために　ここに来た。
Because I just had a great idea!
できれば　すぐにでも 本邸に案内してもらいたいんだが。 その必要は　ございません。
If you seriously mean that, you should surrender, Genthru!
キルア様が　こちらへ 向かっておいでですから。
A shame...
本当？ ええ もうしばらく　お待ちください。
Let me show you
よかったな　ゴン。 うん！
that there are some things worse than death.
さて…　ただ待つのは　退屈で 長く感じるもの。
I'll blow up both your arms.
フッ　ゲームでもして 時間をつぶしませんか？
Use Gyo to protect the one you want to keep.
ゲーム？
After that, I'll blow up your
remaining arm and left leg.
コインは　どちらの手に？
Go ahead and try!
左手。 左手。 左手。
Very well.
ご名答。 では　次は もっと速く行きますよ。
Take this!
さぁ　どちら？ また　左手！ 素晴らしい。
Wh-What happened?
じゃあ　次は　少し本気を出します。
Blood?
さぁ　どっちだ？
First comes rock!
うん　自信薄だが…　多分　右。
Crap... Move... Dodge!
私は　キルア様を 生まれた時から知っている。
Rock... Paper...
せんえつながら 親にも似た感情を抱いている。
Rock!
キルア様を奪おうとしている お前らが憎い。
Did he hit me? No, I tripped.
さぁ　どっちだ？
What was that?
答えろ。
What just happened?
奥様は消え入りそうな声だった。
He sacrificed both hands!
断腸の思いで送り出すのだろう。
But the damage wasn't distributed evenly!
許せねえ。 俺が　俺のやり方で お前らを判断する。
He probably gave up completely on his left hand, protected his right hand with 30% of his aura, and focused the remaining 70% on his legs...
文句は言わせねえ。
to attack me!
あっ…。 あっ…。
I use aura both to explode targets and
to shield my hand from the blast.
カナリア！ 命令を無視して お前らを　ここへ連れて来た罰だ。
If I use it on both hands, I won't have much left for the rest of myself.
それより　いいか。
He took advantage of that!
一度　間違えれば そいつはアウトだ。 ３人とも間違えたら
Still, no one sane would actually try that!
キルア様には　お前らは 先に行ったと伝える。
I gave him a pretty good scare!
二度と会えない所に行ったとな。
Damn...
キルアは…。 黙れ！
This hurts like hell.
てめぇらは　ギリギリのとこで 生かされてるんだ。
But... I'm going for it!
俺の問いにだけ バカみてぇに答えてろ。
I'm done...
どっち？
He's lost his left hand,
and his right is badly injured.
見えない…
And he managed to land a hit on me. He must be satisfied now.
モタモタすんじゃねえ ３秒以内に答えろ。
I'm done being selfish...
おい　３秒　経ったら そいつの首をかっ切れ！ ＯＫ。
Time to get serious!
待て！　左手だ！
Let's do this, Genthru!
俺は　右手！ 私もだ。
Th-This kid's
うっ…。
totally insane!
ダメだ　やっぱり見えない！
He shouldn't have anything to concern me.
どっち？
The card transformed? Paladin's Necklace?!
私は　右手だ。 俺は　左手。
What is he planning? This is your last chance to surrender.
当たりは　左手 これで　残りは１人。
Once I use this, you could end up dead.
行くぜ。 ちょっと待って！
This is my chance. Book.
何だ？　ただの時間稼ぎなら １人　ぶっ殺すぞ。
Obviously, you're never going to surrender.
レオリオ　ナイフ貸して。 えっ？
Take them.
安心してよ 変なことに使うわけじゃ　ない。
I'll silence him. Crushing his windpipe and
knocking him out would be best.
うっ…。
I have one request.
そうか　血を抜いて腫れを…
What is it? Could you leave me this card?
おい　ゴトー！
Bah... He blocked my second attack with Gyo!
誰か　いないのか？
But I did manage to crush his windpipe!
どうなってんだ？
He won't be able to use Book or Gain anymore.
よし　ＯＫ！　よく見える！
Genthru...
どんと来い！ フッ。
You have made the worst mistake you could make.
やるな　じゃあ…。
What's that smell?
さぁ　誰が持ってる？
Book. Oh, so this is gasoline...
後ろの　こっちの人でしょ？
This one is ten times stronger than Little Flower.
フッ　素晴らしい。
All the activation requirements have been met.
ゴトー　ゴンは　まだか？
If I touch you and say, "Bomber,"
the countdown will begin.
キルア！ 何だ　いたんじゃん！　ゴン！
Try to run away...
あと　えっと　クラピカ。 ついでか？
If you still have the strength.
リオレオ！ レオリオ!!
The requirements have been met... for me!
久しぶり！　よく来たな どうした？　ひっでぇ顔だぜ。
First comes rock... This is his earlier attack...
キルアこそ！
If get too close, I'm done for.
ハハハ…。 ハハハ…。
Is he trying to keep me back?
おい　ゴトー！　ゴンが来たら すぐに知らせるはずだったろ？
Rock... Paper...
何してたんだ？ 申し訳ありません。
Rock!
ですが 少し悪ふざけが過ぎました。 大変　失礼いたしました。
A pitfall? But he's falling with me!
いや 楽しませてもらっただけだよ。
It's deep...
そっか　まぁ　いいや。
I can't climb back up.
とにかく　どこでもいいから すぐに出発しようぜ。
But he should be in the same boat.
ここにいると お袋が　うるせぇからさ。
He's ended up cornering himself.
おい！　ゴトー　いいか？
He's gone.
お袋に　何を言われても ついて来んなよ。
Genthru...
ゴン　行こうぜ！　じゃあな。
If a card is removed from
the binder for a minute, it reverts to an item.
キルアがいなくなったら 寂しくなるね。
A rock?!
さぁ　どっちです？
First comes rock...
左手でしょ？
Rock...
えっ　うそ！
W-W-Wait!
そう　トリックです。
I surrender! I surrender!
世の中　正しいことばかりでは ありません。
Rock!
じゃあね　カナリア！
Osu!
あぁ　俺も　そのトリックに だまされたよ。
Summon your binder.
タネ明かしされると 腹立つぐらい　簡単だぜ。
We want you to return the cards you stole from the people you backstabbed.
えっ　そうなの？
On one condition...
恐らく　こういうことだろう。
Use Archangel to heal Bara.
どっちだ？ 左手でしょ？
We have a Clone card.
えっ　何で？　ねぇ　どうして？
Don't worry.
ゴトーは コインを２枚　持っていたのさ。 えっ？　さっき１枚しか…。
That was always part of the plan. We brought six copies of Clone.
とにかく　１枚を右手に隠し持ち もう１枚のコインを上げる。 そして　相手に分かるように
Book...
左手で取る。 この時　少しコツがいる 「どっちだ？」と聞く前に
Gain!
拳を握った状態で　さりげなく 左手のコインを袖の中へ落とす。 あ！
What is your wish?
残ったのは 右手のコインというわけだ。 その通り！ う　腹立つ。
We need you to heal his hands and throat. Actually, can you just heal all his injuries?
まぁ　そのトリックを使ったのは 最後だけだと思うよ。
Easily done.
たとえゲームでも ズルは嫌いだから　ゴトーは。
Then I shall heal his body.
うん。 ハンター試験に合格したんだろ？
I'm healed!
なら　ハンターライセンスを使えば 観光ビザなんてなくても
Then, farewell. All right!
ずっと　外国滞在できるんだぜ。 俺達も　そう言った。
Okay, here's the extra Archangel.
だって　決めたんだもん やること全部やってから使うって。
Gain!
あの時　ヒソカに渡された このプレート！
Next up is Killua. Genthru, we're going to use your binder.
((今みたいに　僕の顔に
Go ahead. Clone on!
一発ぶち込むことができたら 受け取ろう))
Breath of Archangel has reached
its maximum card limit.
((それまで そのプレートは　君に預ける))
Clone will be destroyed.
このプレートは　ヒソカに
W-W-Wait!
顔面パンチのおまけ付きで たたき返す！
What's going on?! Did I do something wrong?
そうしないうちは 絶対　ハンターライセンスは使わない！
No, it's Goreinu. Huh?
くじら島にだって帰れないよ！
He used Clone or Transform to increase the
number of Breath of Archangel vouchers.
ふん　で　ヒソカの居場所は？ えっと…。 やっぱりな…。
So two of his vouchers became
Breath of Archangel cards.
私が知っているよ　ゴン。 えっ　本当？ 何でだ？
Another player has used Contact to reach you.
本人に聞いたからだ。
Yo, it's Goreinu.
あの時か…。
Looks like you won.
いや　講習が終わった後だ。 だが　関係があるんだろ？ まぁな。
If you plan to use Breath of Archangel
to heal these murderers, the trade is off!
前から聞きたかったことだが
You okay with using it on me? Of course.
あの時　ヒソカに何を言われた？
I am an assassin. Eh?
「クモ」について…。
I've killed more people than these guys.
((「クモ」について いいことを教えよう))
Each player in this game risks their
life in one way or another.
「幻影旅団」のことか。
That doesn't make it okay to kill others.
ヒソカに「旅団」のことを 話した覚えは　ないから １次試験の時に レオリオとの話を聞かれたか
But all the people I've killed were
not nearly as prepared to die.
他の誰かが話したか…。
I'm worse than these guys.
クモは　「旅団」のシンボルだ。
No, you aren't like them.
故に　「旅団」に近しい者は 奴らを　そう呼ぶ。
I like you, but I hate their guts!
それを知っていたヒソカの情報に 興味があってな。
That isn't a valid reason! I don't need a reason...
なるほどな。
What counts is how I feel.
プライドの高い　お前が
Aren't you guys the same way?
甘んじて　ヒソカの試験放棄を 受け入れた理由が　分かったぜ
But we don't think it's right to let them die because we hate them.
それで　講習後に ヒソカに問いただした。 ((９月１日 ヨークシンシティで待ってる))
In battle, both sides risk their lives, and are prepared to kill.
９月１日？ ９月１日って　半年以上　先だね。
But that doesn't apply once the fight is over.
ヨークシンシティで　何かあるの？
I haven't forgiven Genthru for
killing all those players...
あっ！ 世界最大のオークションがある。
But the three of us agreed before the fight
そうだ ９月１日から１０日までの間
that we'd bring six Clone cards.
世界中から　珍品　希少品 国宝級の貴重品が集まる オークションだ。 それらを目指して 海千山千の亡者達が
I don't really remember why we decided that, but it wasn't based on logic or reason.
欲望を満たすために　やって来る。
It was just the decision that came naturally to us.
世界で一番　金の集まる場所だ。 へぇ。
Once the fight was over and we'd
obtained Breath of Archangel, we planned to heal everyone.
そこへ　「旅団」の奴らも来るのか？ 奴らは盗賊団だ。
All three of us made the decision,
so we wanted to stick to it.
そんな絶好の機会を 狙わないわけないだろう。 そういうわけで その日　ヒソカは
But I understand how you feel,
and we can't change your mind. Sorry, Killua...
ヨークシンシティのどこかに いるはずだ。
Could you wait a little longer?
なるほど　９月１日ね 分かった　ありがとう。
No problem. I'll recover on my own in a while.
じゃあ　私は　ここで失礼する。 えっ？
There's only one Breath of Archangel left.
キルアとも再会できたし 私は区切りがついた。
Only one? Isn't that the original?
オークションに参加するためには 金も必要だしな。
Use it on Genthru.
これからは　本格的なハンターとして 雇い主を探す。
I'm fine...
そっか…　じゃあ　俺も 故郷へ帰るとするか。 レオリオも？
Okay, let's use Accompany to go to Masadora.
やっぱり 医者の夢は捨て切れねえ。
Yeah.
国立医大に受かれば　これで バカ高い授業料は 免除されるからな。
Hey, wait up... Fine, you can have Breath of Archangel. Huh?
これから帰って 猛勉強しねえとな。
Really? Are you sure?
うん　頑張ってね。
Yeah, actually... Before you told me all this,
I planned to give it to you.
また　会おうぜ。 そうだな　次は…。
Not just Archangel, but all of our cards. What?!
９月１日　ヨークシンシティで！
Tsezgerra, his team, and I all agreed.
じゃあな！
We've decided to give up on the game.
バイバイ！
Wow, I'm completely healed!
あっという間に ２人になっちゃったね。
Oh, so Mr. Battera...
ねぇ　どうする？ どうするって 特訓するに決まってんだろ。
Yeah, he paid Tsezgerra and his
team for breaking his promise.
えっ？　何の？　遊ばないの？
I got four billion out of it. Four billion?! Hey...
お前な　さっき　何つった？
Share some of the wealth! Wh-What are you talking about?
そんなんでヒソカを 一発でも殴れると思ってんのか？
Each of the four of us gets one billion!
うっ…。
Eh?!
半年どころか １０年経っても無理だっつうの！
It's only fair... I couldn't have done this on my own.
はい。
It was only possible because
I teamed up with you guys.
いいか？　分かりやすく言うと これがヒソカ　これがハンゾーな。
I can't believe it...
ふむ　ふむ。
You're such a nice guy!
ヒソカとハンゾーの力の差を これぐらいだとすると…。 お前との差は…。
Anyway, you can take all the cards. On one condition!
ここ！　かなりオマケでな。
That gives you ninety-nine restricted slot cards.
ちょっと　ムカつく。
Leaving only #0.
じゃあ　キルアは　どこなのさ？
One card to go... Yeah.
俺か？　うん。 まぁ　ここだろうな。
Ninety-seven, ninety-eight...
うん　俺って謙虚
And this is...
へぇ　ハンゾーのほうが強いの？ ふん。
Maid Panda
A species on the
verge of extinction.
Tidy, loves to cook,
and some individuals
enjoy Western clothing
and gardening.
Excellent at taking
care of human children. ninety-nine!
真顔で言うな　ハズいだろ。
This announcement is for all players.
俺　自分と相手の強さの差なんて はっきりと測れないよ！ バカ　いいんだよ こんなの俺も適当なんだから。
A player has collected ninety-nine
restricted slot cards.
ゴンだって 何となくなら分かるだろ？ 経験　積むと その精度が少し良くなるだけさ。 それに　強い奴ほど 強さを隠すのも　うまいからな。
Ten minutes from now, in honor of this event, there will be a quiz contest
for all Greed Island players. There will be one hundred total questions
あんまり　これに頼るのも よくねえよ。 そうなんだ。
dealing with restricted slot cards.
まぁ　何にしても　ヒソカは強い。 うん。 並大抵のことじゃ
The player who has the most
correct answers will receive
半年で一矢報いるのは　無理だ。 うん。
#0 Ruler's Blessing as a prize.
ゴン　金は　あるか？ えっ？ うん　実は　そろそろヤバい。
Please wait with your binders open.
俺も　あんま持ってない。
Questions about restricted slot cards, huh?
そこでだ　特訓と金儲けの 一石二鳥の場所がある。
I get it. The questions are probably
designed so that players
特訓と金儲け？
who mainly stole cards can't answer them.
天空闘技場さ！
Someone's coming!
天空…　闘技場？
Wait, more over here!
うん！ 別れたクラピカとレオリオに
The long battle has finally
reached its final stage.